被你发现了
You got me!
我投降
I give up.
天呐  天呐  她可算来了
Oh, boy, oh, boy! She's finally here!
你好  我是你的新家庭操作系统
Hello. I'm your new home-operating system.
我叫露西  你叫什么
My name is Lucy. What's yours?
我叫里克·卡塞尔
Uh, my name is Rick Castle, and...
还有
and...
我老婆最近离开了我
My wife just left me.
哎呦  真替你难过  里克
Yikes. Sucks to be you, Rick.
你就这点力气吗
Can't you hit any harder than that?
看来不是了
I'll take that as a yes.
来吧
Come on.
听我说  你还可以退出的
Listen. You can still back out.
-我可以自己来  -绝对不行
- I can do this on my own. - Not a chance.
如果不是你  我死定了  所以我欠你的
I'd be dead if not for you, which means I owe you.
再说  我一向想为纽约警局做数字调查员
Besides, I always wanted to be a digital investigator for the NYPD.
这是份真正的工作  维克拉姆
It's a real job, Vikram.
你要协助12分局侦破凶杀案
You'll be helping the 12th solve homicides.
白天的工作
By day.
晚上  我披上披风
By night, I'll wear a cape
寻找派遣杀手小队杀我们
and track down the mysterious villain
还杀了替罪羊艾莉森·海德的
who sent a hit squad to kill us
神秘坏蛋
and scapegoat-murdered Allison Hyde.
拜托你认真点好吗
Would you take this seriously, please?
我为了走上这条路  毁了我的婚姻
I just blew up my marriage to go down this path.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我应该给你机会退出才对
Hell, I should be giving you the chance to back out.
不
No.
如果我不为蕾切尔和其他人伸张正义
If I don't get justice for Rachel and for everyone else,
就不会有别人去做了
no one will.
我们得尽快查清
We just got to do this fast.
我们万万急不得
Fast is the one speed we can't move.
我们得小心行事
We need stealth.
如果这事拖太久
If this takes any longer,
卡塞尔会猜到我们在做什么
then Castle is gonna figure out what we're doing.
那又如何
And if he does?
他会插手  会使自己陷入危险
He's gonna step in, and he's gonna put himself in danger.
那就确保他离得远远的
Then make sure he stays away.
贝克特跟你说过他们分手的事吗
Has Beckett told you anything about the breakup yet?
完全没有  你跟卡塞尔谈过吗
Not a word. You talked to Castle about it?
没有  我给他留了一堆留言
No. And I've left him a bunch of messages.
真让人动摇
Shakes your faith.
看来真没有什么是永恒的
I guess nothing in life is permanent.
跟被害人说去吧
Tell that to the victim.
贝克特警监
Captain Beckett.
您怎么来外勤了
What brings you out into the field?
工作啊
Work.
你以为我当上警监
What, do you think I'm gonna be stuck in the office
-就会成天做办公室了吗  -我们
- just 'cause I'm captain? - We--
-逃犯是谁  -尚未查到身份
- So, who's our fugitive? - No I.D. yet.
但套衫是里克斯监狱的标配
But the jumpsuit is standard issue at Rikers.
但他们说他们没有囚犯越狱
But they say that none of their prisoners have gone missing.
我们已经让他们封锁监狱
We had them lock down the facility,
但清点1.4万名犯人得要好一会儿了
but a 14,000-inmate head count is gonna take some time.
-查过指纹吗  -是的  目前没结果
- You run his prints? - Yeah. So far, nothing.
没结果  他是判刑重罪犯
Nothing? The guy's a convicted felon.
他的指纹肯定记录在案
His fingerprints are on file.
可能是系统故障
Probably a glitch.
便携扫描器什么的
You know, those portable scanners...
-有时候不好使  -嗯
- Sometimes they're wonky. - Yeah.
这可能不是凶杀吗
Is there any chance that this wasn't a homicide?
绝无可能
None.
要用那根树枝
It took brute force
刺穿被害人尸体需要极大力气
to puncture the victim's body with that branch.
是有人捅上去的
Someone had to shove him onto it.
里克斯岛的越狱囚犯
So how does an escaped convict from Rikers Island
怎么会跑来中央公园深处
end up in the middle of Central Park
还没被人发现
without anyone seeing him?
当时很晚了
It was late.
尸斑证实死亡时间
Lividity puts the time of death
为午夜到凌晨两点
between midnight and 2:00 a.m.
好吧  继续查指纹
All right, keep running prints.
我去周围走走  看看有什么发现
I'm gonna walk around and see what I can find.
你没回我电话
You didn't call me back.
是啊  抱歉了
Yeah, I'm... I'm sorry about that.
没事  不过你呢
Oh, that's okay. But are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
我就是有点迷茫
I'm just a-a little lost
想给自己点空间想清楚
and taking some space so I can figure things out.
我只希望我没有伤他太深
I just hope that I haven't hurt him too much.
妹子  拜托
Girl, please.
卡塞尔是个大老爷们
Castle is a grown-ass man,
他知道你是多么爱他
and he knows that you love him very much.
他肯定没事的
I'm sure he's okay.
我不知道该怎么办才好  露西
I just don't know what to do, Lucy.
我列了一张顶级离婚律师的名单
I've compiled a list of top-ranked divorce attorneys.
不  我不想离婚
No! I don't want a divorce.
我希望我老婆回来  我要怎么做到
I want my wife back. How do I do that?
我不知道
I don't know.
你最初怎么追到她的  里克
How did you get her in the first place, Rick?
贝克特有跟你谈过吗
Has Beckett talked to you?
让我们谈谈
Give us a minute.
你知道我不会把她的话说出来的
You know better than to think I would betray her confidence.
该死  蕾妮  告诉我
Damn it, Lanie, tell me...
贝克特为什么瞒着我
Why is Beckett keeping me in the dark?
你去年消失了俩月也好意思问
The man who went Houdini for two months last year?
不是我有意的诶  我是被绑了
Whoa. I didn't Houdini. I was Houdinied.
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
你回来时  她没有二话地接受了你
When you came back, she accepted you without question,
你现在也该给她点空间
so you can damn well give her some space now.
我不能失去她
I can't lose her.
我知道
I know.
那是12分局的吗
Is that from the 12th?
卡塞尔
Castle.
逃狱囚犯  年轻  二十一二
Escaped prisoner. Young... maybe 21, 22?
那是
Is that...
铁栅栏吗
Iron fence?
树枝
Tree branch.
查到身份了吗
Got an I.D. yet?
我不会告诉你的
I'm not telling you.
我见过这个红魔
I've seen this devil before.
别闹了
Just stop.
查谋杀案已经不是你的工作了
Working murders is not your job anymore.
他肯定要垮掉的
He's gonna be an absolute wreck.
我们就要保证他不失控
And it's our job not to let him spin out.
这就是CDRK的作用
That's what the C.D.R.K. is for.
卡塞尔抑郁营救装备
"Castle depression rescue kit."
电子游戏  苏门答腊麝香猫咖啡豆
Video games, Sumatran Civet Coffee beans,
原版《阴阳魔界》画质增强蓝光版
enhanced blu-rays of the original "Twilight zone," and...
-还有这个  -9汪汪
- this. - 9-woof-woof?
30分钟内送狗狗上门
Puppies at your doorstep in 30 minutes or less.
狗狗诶
Puppies.
早上好  我的小可爱们
Good morning, my lovelies.
生命多么美好啊
Isn't it great to be alive?
理查德  你没事吧
Richard, are you feeling okay?
好极了
Never better.
因为我知道要怎么赢回贝克特了
Because I know how to win Beckett back.
她希望你赢回她吗
Is she wanting to be won back?
我们最初认识是  是我顽皮的魅力
When we first met, it was my roguish charm
让贝克特放下防线
that caused Beckett to drop her guard,
但我神探夏洛克一般的天才
but it was my Sherlockian skills
才是她爱上我的原因
that made her fall in love with me.
我只需要跟她一起解决几桩案子
I just have to solve a few cases with her
让她明白  我们合力依然能创造奇迹
to show her that, together, we are still magic.
理查德  你知道
Richard, you do know
你不能再直接闯进分局
that you cannot just barge your way into the precinct
靠花言巧语插手办案了吧
and talk your way onto a case anymore.
我是有执照私家侦探
I am a licensed private investigator.
我不需要分局也能破案
I don't need a precinct to solve a case.
这个纹身是在一名死囚犯身上看到的
Now, this tattoo was on the body of a dead convict
他的尸体在中央公园被发现
found in Central Park.
我知道我以前看到过的
I know I've seen it somewhere before.
但我不知道是在哪
I just don't know where.
我知道
I do.
里克岛清点完了
Um, Rikers completed their head count.
所有囚犯都在
All inmates are accounted for.
那被害人的囚衣是哪来的
So, where'd the vic's jumpsuit come from?
道具店
A costume shop.
无名氏不是犯人
Our John Doe was not an inmate.
他是大学生
He was a college student.
肩膀上的纹身  是哈德逊大学
Tattoo on his shoulder is the original mascot design
红魔队吉祥物的原始设计
of the hudson U. Red Devils.
我查过大学网站
Now, I checked the college website.
彼得·加伯.
Peter Garber.
21岁  主修市场营销
21 years old, majoring in marketing.
但这也无法解释套衫的事
But that doesn't explain the jumpsuit.
现在是十月份
You guys, it's october.
在大学里  万圣节基本要庆祝一个月
Halloween's basically a month-long party in college.
哎哟  神圣的学术殿堂
Ah, the hallowed halls of academia.
我可记忆犹新呢
I remember them well.
在我的学校可更像神圣的嗑药殿堂
More like the hallowed halls of crackheads in my schools.
你们去彼得的兄弟会看看
Head over to Peter's frat house.
问问他的室友
Interview his roommates.
我去把这坏消息告诉校长
I'm gonna break the bad news to the dean.
好
Right.
你好  我是贝克特警监
Hi. I'm captain Beckett.
我得跟费勒校长谈谈  谢谢
I need to speak with dean Feller, please.
您这样的畅销书作家加入我校将是莫大荣幸
It will be nice to have a best-selling author on the faculty.
欢迎加入哈德逊大家庭  卡塞尔先生
Welcome to the Hudson family, Mr. Castle.
费勒校长  拜托  请叫我卡塞尔教授
Oh, please, dean Feller, call me "Professor Castle."
贝克特警监
Captain Beckett.
居然在这儿见到你了
Fancy seeing you here.
卡塞尔  我知道你想干什么
Castle, I know what you're doing.
我在回馈社会
I'm giving back to the community
培养年轻人
by molding young minds?
你不能参与这案子
You're not joining this case.
你们二位不是结婚了吗
Aren't you two married?
是  没错
Yes, we are.
费勒校长  这位是12分局的贝克特警监
Dean Feller, meet captain Beckett of the 12th precinct.
是  我们夫妻俩需要单独聊聊
Yes. And husband and wife need a moment in private.
慢点
Hang on.
我弄了一小时才把这玩意儿系好
It took me an hour to tie this.
你在停尸间看到尸体上的纹身了是吧
Oh, you saw the tattoo at the morgue, didn't you?
我只记得在停尸间见到了蕾妮
I saw Lanie at the morgue.
至于胸口伤势惨不忍睹的尸体上
I can't recall if I saw other things
有没有别的东西  我就不记得了
on bodies with gruesome chest wounds.
我问你  你为了变身成为教授
Let me ask you... how large of a donation check did you write
开了多大的支票
in order to become a professor?
客座教授而已
Guest professor.
听着  我无意插手你的案子
Look... I have no desire to interfere with your case,
但要是我在这教书时跟你产生了交集
But I can't help it if my path crosses with yours
我也没办法啊
while I'm teaching here.
卡塞尔  我让你给我点时间
Castle, I asked for time.
你怎么就不能给
Why can't you give me that?
因为你需要我
Because you need me.
我现在没工夫说这些
I... I can't do this right now.
-凯特  -抱歉打扰了
- Kate. - I'm sorry to interrupt,
但我必须知道为什么有警察来到我的校园
But I really need to know why there are police on my campus.
你们这里的一个学生  彼得·加伯
A student of yours, Peter Garber,
昨晚在中央公园被杀了
was found murdered in Central Park last night.
太可怕了
That's awful.
他是个优秀的年轻人  是模范学生
He was a wonderful young man... a model student.
他还是今年的奖学金得主
He won this year's fellowship award.
我需要查看他所有的档案
Well, I'll need access to all of his files,
还需要一个私密点的房间
as well as a discreet room
对他的老师和同学进行问话
to interview his teachers and friends.
当然
Of course.
至于你
And as for you...
教授  现在是警方查案
Professor, this is a police investigation.
请你离远点
Stay out of it.
她真会开玩笑
She's such a kidder.
有发现了
We got something.
怎么了
What's wrong?
卡塞尔在这里
Castle's here.
他给自己买了个博士身份好掺合进来
He bought himself a PHD to get in on this case.
你们不准用任何方式跟他合作
You guys are not to work with him in any way.
明白吗
Is that understood?
-明白  -当然  绝对的
- Yeah. - Yes. Absolutely.
-好  有什么发现  -有嫌疑人了
-Okay, so, what do we got? - A suspect.
-是吗  -彼得是ΒΩΡ
- Yeah? - Peter was pledge master
兄弟会的预备会员负责人
at the beta omega rho fraternity house.
我猜猜  他欺负了新人  有人威胁要报仇
Let me guess... he hazed someone and they threatened revenge?
其实正相反  斯科特·鲍威尔
The opposite, actually. Scott Powell.
前ΒΩ兄弟会的
Former beta omega.
斯科特欺负了不少预备会员
Scott terrorized a group of pledges,
有一个还进了医院
got one of them sent to the hospital.
于是彼得举报了斯科特  让他被兄弟会除名
So Peter turned Scott in, got him booted from the frat.
好吧  听起来像是动机
Okay, well, that sounds like motive.
把他带回来问问
Let's bring him in for questioning.
这样可能行不通
Yeah, that might not be the right approach.
斯科特的父亲是个辩护律师
Scott's dad is a defense attorney.
当初学校想开出斯科特的时候
When the university tried to expel Scott,
他爸就威胁过要上诉
Daddy threatened to sue.
所以斯科特是不会跟我们开口的
So Scott's not gonna talk to us.
除非我们能不知不觉地
Unless we can get him to talk
把他的话套出来
without him realizing that he's talking?
你们打算怎么做
How do you plan on doing that?
你在市场营销课上表现咋样
So, how's the talent in your marketing class?
靠谱着呢  尤其有个叫珍妮的金发美女
Oh, solid. Especially this hot blonde named Jenny.
-你说真的  -当然
- Aw, for real? - Yeah.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
你知道那个兄弟会的男生
Hey, did you see that that frat boy got murdered
昨晚在公园被杀了吗
last night in the park?
知道  听说他被刺穿了
Aw, yeah. I heard he got impaled.
叫彼得什么的
Ah, was it Peter, uh...something.
他是哪个兄弟会的
What house was he in?
不知道
I have no idea.
伙计你知道死的那哥们儿是哪个兄弟会的吗
Hey, bro, you know what frat the dead dude's from?
不  警官  我可不知道
No, officer, I sure don't.
什么
What?
我们可不是条子  伙计
We ain't cops, man.
哥们儿  你都40多的人了
Dude, you look like you're 40.
小婊砸怎么说话呢  我上周还被查过身份证
Bitch, please. I got carded last week.
是啊  退休协会的会员卡吧
Yeah, for your aarp card.
还有你搭档  耳毛都没除干净
And your partner's growing ear hair in front of my eyes.
好吧  滑稽哥
All right, funny man.
我们听说你跟彼得·加伯有仇
We heard that you had a hate-on for Peter Garber.
能告诉我们你昨晚在哪吗
So you want to tell us where you were last night?
不能  不过你们可以打给我的律师
No. But you can call my lawyer.
他肯定会好好收拾你们的
He's gonna get a real kick out of you guys.
祝愉快
Have a nice day.
对了  记得多吃点纤维有好处
Oh, and remember... fiber's your friend.
我没有老人的耳毛  对吧
I don't really have old-man ear hair, do I?
伙计们
Guys.
你们不会真以为
You didn't really think
可以靠《龙虎少年队》那套审头号嫌疑人吧
you could "Jump Street" the prime suspect, did you?
卡塞尔  你来干什么
Castle, what are you doing here?
我听说了斯科特·鲍威尔欺负新人的事
I heard about the Scott Powell hazing incident.
我想向纽约警方提供我的私家侦探服务
I thought I'd offer the NPYD my PI Services.
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
-免费的哦  -不用  谢谢
- Free of charge. - No, thanks.
好吧
All right, fine.
那我只能凭借我作为教职工的新身份特权
I guess I'll just use my newfound faculty privileges
亲自跟斯科特聊聊了
to talk to Scott on my own.
他30分钟后要上当代文学课
He's got a contemporary-lit class in 30 minutes.
他们请了位非常特别的嘉宾讲师
They have a very special guest speaker...
一位粗犷帅气的畅销书作家
A certain ruggedly handsome best-selling author.
我们也许能利用他
He just might be the angle we need
套出斯科特的话来
to get this guy Scott to talk.
贝克特给我们下了直接命令
Beckett gave us a direct order.
哪样会让她更生气
Will she be more upset
是卡塞尔在我们之前破了案
when she finds out Castle solved this case before us,
还是让她发现我们在跟卡塞尔合作
or when she finds out we've been cooperating with him?
也许我的秘密武器就是你们在找的突破口哦
Perhaps my secret weapon is the loophole you're looking for.
什么秘密武器
What secret weapon?
这里有人坐吗
Anybody sitting there?
你啊
Uh, you are.
-谢了  -不客气
- Thanks. - Yeah.
我是斯科特
Uh, I'm Scott.
克拉拉
Clara.
你知道这个叫理查德·卡塞尔的家伙吗
So, you know anything about this Richard Castle guy?
一点点
A little.
他是个无牵无挂的罪案小说家
He's an irreverent crime novelist with a carefree spirit
而且跟感叹号有仇
and a hatred of exclamation marks.
至少我听说是这样
Or so I hear.
我几年前看过他一个采访
Well, I saw an interview with him a few years ago.
他太努力想装酷了
He was trying way too hard to be cool.
他年纪大了应该会成熟点吧
I'm sure he's mellowed with age.
死亡  或睡眠
"To die, to sleep...
睡眠  或许就会有梦
To sleep, perchance to dream."
也可能不会
Or not.
没错  这就是矛盾之处
"Aye, for there's the rub.
在这死亡的长眠中  会有怎样的梦境
For in this sleep of death, what dreams may come?"
威廉·莎士比亚  游吟诗人
William Shakespeare, the bard.
此人对暴力和谋杀的熟悉不压于任何人
A man as intimate with violence and murder as any in history.
谁能告诉我经典的凶杀动机有哪些
Who can tell me the classic motivations for murder?
你  穿非挖苦T恤那个
You, in the printed non-ironic tee
过分殷勤的金发女郎旁边那个
beside the too-friendly blonde.
我吗
Oh, me?
是你
Yes.
是什么可能驱使一个人去杀人呢
What might drive a person to murder?
不知道  复仇吗
I don't know. Revenge?
复仇
Revenge.
一个人蒙冤  声誉被毁
A man wronged, his reputation besmirched,
于是在激愤中杀了人
so he strikes out in passion.
也许有人会觉得这无可厚非
Some might consider his actions justified.
还有什么可能让人想要杀戮呢
What else might drive a person to kill?
被迫读你写的书
Being forced to read one of your books?
虽然那更有可能让人想要自杀
Though that's probably more of a motive for suicide.
你上一本读过的书是什么
And, uh, what was the last book you read...
《禅与欺负嬉皮士的艺术》吗
"Zen and the art of hazing hipsters"?
我欣赏你跑来引述莎士比亚的句子
Oh, I love how you come in here quoting Shakespeare
好像这就能提升
like it's just gonna magically elevate
你写的那些乏味的小说似的
that treadmill fiction you write.
乏味的小说
Treadmill fi--
出去
Get out.
立刻
Now.
我没意见
Works for me.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
到底什么情况
What the hell?
先是那些警察过来试探  然后又是那个蠢货
First the cops try and front me, and then that clown.
警察
Cops?
一个过去兄弟会的哥们昨晚被杀了
A guy from my old frat got killed last night.
彼得·加伯
Peter Garber.
他们认为我恨他
They think I hated him
他害我因为整了几个菜鸟被踢出会
'cause he got me kicked out for hazing some newbies.
但是我上个学期一直在试图修复关系
But I spent the last semester trying to make amends.
-和彼得  -是的
- With Peter? - Yeah.
我跟他说我很抱歉  他说没事了
Told him I was sorry, you know, and he said we were cool.
甚至还让我帮他个忙
He even asked me for a favor.
他说他需要一个安静的地方学习
Said he needed a quiet place to study
避开兄弟会宿舍
Away from the frat house.
我在房屋住宅工作
I work at residential housing,
所以我悄悄给他安排了一间空屋住
so I hooked him up with an empty apartment on the D.L.
这些你为什么不告诉警察
Why didn't you tell the cops?
我爸是个律师
My dad's a lawyer,
他教过我千万不要相信警察
and he taught me you never trust the police.
事实上  他还教过我
Actually, you know, he also taught me
金发姑娘要有趣的多
that blondes are more fun.
我们一会儿出去玩玩吧
What say we go out later?
我和哥们昨晚发现了一个很棒的酒吧  叫做厄运
My crew and I found this great bar last night called jinx.
我挺想去  但是我明早要装
I'd love to, but I'm actually getting fitted for an iron lung
铁肺了
in the morning.
再见
Bye.
维克拉姆  你查到了什么
Okay, Vikram. What have you got?
我也许知道是谁杀了艾莉森·海德了
I might have identified Allison Hyde's killer.
我调了海德死亡时间段
Pulled footage from the hotel cameras
酒店的监控录像
around the time Hyde was killed.
确认了每个人的身份  除了他
Managed to I.D. everyone, except this guy.
这不能说明什么
Look, this doesn't mean anything.
有很多人
There's plenty of people
都不在我们的面部识别系统中
who aren't in our facial-recognition database.
不光用了我们的系统
Didn't just use ours.
我黑进了国家安全局
I snuck into the NSA,
用他们最高机密数据库查了这个人
ran him through their top-secret database.
那是公民自由的噩梦
It's a civil-liberties nightmare,
但是却非常全面
but very comprehensive.
这位衣冠楚楚的先生完全是个鬼魂
Our well-dressed man is a total ghost.
除非你认识捉鬼队的人
So unless you know a ghostbuster,
我们就没辙了
we're out of luck.
我知道一个人
I-I might know somebody.
他以前帮过我
He's helped me out in the past,
而且他跟这个世界有联系
and he's connected to this world.
但理论上来说他是个死人
But he's technically dead,
所以你得把他挖出来
which means you're gonna have to dig him up.
确认一下  你是说他伪造了自己的死亡
Just to be clear, you mean he faked his own death
现在以一个新的身份生活
and now he's hiding under a new identity
而我需要找出这个新身份
that you need me to uncover?
-是的  -好  我可不想真拿铲子挖人
- Yeah. - Good. 'cause I'm not a huge fan of shoveling.
有没有可能彼得是真想找个公寓学习呢
What are the odds Peter really wanted this apartment for studying?
要我说可能性为零
I'd say those odds are less than zero.
纽约警局
NYPD.
我以为彼得的专业是市场营销
I thought Peter was majoring in marketing,
不是中世纪酷刑
not medieval torture.
这些不是刑具  这是个性虐调教室
This stuff isn't for torture. It's a bdsm dungeon.
怎么啦  我读过《五十度灰》显然彼得也读过
What? I read "Fifty shades," and clearly so had Peter.
看看
Okay.
我想这个似乎不止《五十度灰》
I'm thinking this is a little less "Fifty shades"
而是《致命诱惑》了
and a little more "Fatal attraction."
他和他的捆绑爱好者恋人
His bondage-curious lover
在这儿筑巢来满足自己的一切幻想
set up shop here to fulfill all their fantasies.
角色扮演
Role play.
可能是变态罪犯和邪恶狱警
Perhaps kinky convict and wicked warden.
总之  彼得想要结束关系
D-- anyway, Peter tries to break it off.
这个被抛弃的恋人  狂怒地想杀人
The lover, spurned, flies into a murderous rage,
于是在公园里钉死了他
and then impales him in the park.
好吧  我们得弄清楚彼得在这里
All right. We need to figure out who Peter's been...
和谁取乐
entertaining here.
那意味着我们要开始敲门了
That means we need to start knocking on some doors,
-还有调监控录像  -有个简单的办法
- pulling surveilLance footage. - There's an easier way.
兄弟会男孩喜欢八卦情史
Frat boys love to kiss and tell.
如果说谁会知道彼得和什么人在一起
If anyone knows who Peter was involved with,
一定是他的兄弟们
It will be his brothers.
没错  但是他们不太愿交待
Yeah, but they weren't exactly forthcoming
-我们之前问过他们  -没错
- When we interviewed them earlier. - Yeah.
因为你们是"男人"
That's because you're "The man."
但我不是
But I'm not.
我进来了
I'm in.
她进去了
She's in.
我们听见了
We heard.
你知道这不是她第一次参加兄弟会派对  卡塞尔
You know this isn't her first frat party, Castle.
你是想让我好受点儿吗
You trying to make me feel better?
可以理解
You know, it's understandable
你现在这种过度保护倾向
if you're feeling a little overprotective right now
考虑到你和贝克特的事...
with what's been happening with Beckett.
我们的事  是我要让她回到我身边
"What's happening" is I'm getting her back.
你确定这是正确的做法吗
Are you sure this is the right way to do it?
她明确表示不想让你参与这个案子
She was pretty clear that she did not want you working this case.
她就是因为我们一起破案才爱上我的
Working cases together is why she fell in love with me.
所以我一定要解决这件案子
That's why I'm going to do whatever it takes
无论付出怎样的代价
to solve this case.
包括让你女儿
Including sending your daughter
穿得像个性感天使  进入一个
into a house full of drunken frat boys,
全是醉鬼的兄弟会吗
dressed like a slutty angel?
开门  快开门
Open it. Open it.
彼得的事真让人伤心
It's so sad about Peter.
你跟他很熟吗
Were you close with him?
他是个帅哥
He was a hottie.
他一定有不少女朋友  是吧
I bet he had a lot of girlfriends, huh?
-她的眼睛在上面呢  -你干啥
- Her eyes are up here. - What are you doing?
-我能搞定  -是吗
- I got this. - Do you?
我只听见一大堆调情的话
'cause I'm hearing a whole lot of flirting
没有任何关于彼得约会对象的信息
and zero fact-finding on who Peter was dating.
兄弟  我先看见她的
Hey, bro. I saw her first.
找你自己的妹子去
Get your own girl.
我是说真的  走开老头
I mean it. Hit the road, old man.
老头
Old man?
这个老头要痛扁你一顿
This old man is gonna kick your ass.
在啤酒乒乓球上
At beer pong.
啤酒乒乓球挑战  各位
Beer-pong challenge, everyone!
你到底有什么计划
What exactly is your strategy?
要想让一个人信任你
To get any man to confide in you,
你得先赢得他的尊重
you must first earn his respect.
要想赢得他的尊重  我需要放开手脚
To do that, I need to bro down.
谢谢
Thank you.
好嘞
All right.
10块钱  我赌卡塞尔
10 bucks on Castle.
行啊
You're on.
警监你好
Hey, captain.
你们在这儿干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
-监视  -盘查
- SurveilLance. - Canvassing.
吃瘪吧  弗兰肯斯坦
In your face, Frankenstein.
听我们解释
We can explain.
我就跟你们提了一个要求
I ask one thing of you guys.
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
彼得的事真是太糟糕了
Terrible thing about Peter.
真希望我有机会了解他
Wish I would have gotten to know him better.
你跟茱莉聊过吗  她都垮掉了吧
You, uh, spoken to Julie? She must be devastated.
茱莉是谁
Who's Julie?
难道不是彼得女朋友的名字
Isn't that Peter's girlfriend's name?
彼得一心想着那个熟女教授  利斯特罗姆博士
Peter was all about this cougar professor, Dr. Lillstrom.
他把课余时间都花在她身上
He spent all of his free time with her,
如果你懂我的意思的话
if you know what I mean.
哦  某些人潜台词学得不错
Oh, someone didn't skip his lesson on subtext.
好了  最后一投  教授  来吧
All right, last shot, professor. Bring it.
谢了
Thank you.
喝
Drink.
好了  派对到此为止
All right. Party's over.
除非你们想让我查身份证件
Unless you want me to start checking IDs.
投的真漂亮  我们应该组队
That was a nice shot. We should team up.
我们可以大战三百合
We could pong hustle.
卡塞尔  回家去  你喝醉了
Castle, go home. You're drunk.
我没醉  我在案这个破
I'm not drunk. I'm casing the crack.
破  破  破这个案
Crack -- crack... Cracking the case.
你酒量太小
You're a lightweight.
走吧  老爸  该回去了
Come on, dad. Time to go.
好吧  天使  你来开车
Okay, angel. You're driving.
你作为一个警察真是性感
You're pretty hot for a cop.
-我有枪  -好吧
- I have a gun. - Right.
-贝克特  -是我  维克拉姆
- Beckett  - It's Vikram.
我发现你那假死的人在新泽西复活了
I found your dead guy resurrected in New Jersey.
我知道你能在哪找到他
And I know where you can find him.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
你到这里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
抱歉扰了你清净  不过你在我被诬陷
Sorry to shake your snow globe, but you helped me once
谋杀瓦肯·西蒙斯的时候帮过我一次
when I was being framed for Vulcan Simmons's murder,
而我现在需要你再帮我一次
and I need your help again.
休想  我欠的已经还清了
Forget it. I paid all my debts.
这个男人杀死了一名和布莱肯
This man killed an assistant A.G.
洗钱案有关的总检察长助理
connected to Bracken's dirty-money scheme.
我不认识他
I don't know him.
他为布莱肯的搭档效力
He works for Bracken's partner,
一个隐藏在中情局内部的神秘人  性别未知
some mystery man or woman deep inside the CIA.
你为什么就不能放下这件事
Why can't you just leave this alone?
那不是我的作风
I wasn't built that way.
听着  我在这里过得很好
Look, I've got a good thing here.
有一个爱我的女人  全新的生活
A woman who loves me, a new life.
我很快乐  你也可以
I'm happy. You could be, too.
你只需要放手
You just have to let it go.
我做不到
I can't.
你凭什么认为瓦肯·西蒙斯死后
What makes you think the drug shipments stopped
贩毒就结束了
with Vulcan Simmons's death?
每一个毒贩都有一个标识  说是指纹也行
Every narcotic has a signature, a fingerprint, if you will.
找到他的标识  你就能顺着查下去了
You find his, you pick up the trail.
-谢谢  -不必
- Thank you. - Don't.
你会害死自己的
You're gonna get yourself killed.
走吧  狗狗
Come on, boy.
你这年龄已经斗不动酒了  儿啊
Oh. You're getting too old for drinking games, kiddo.
那是为了破案
It was for the case.
就是那个凯瑟琳不停把你踢出来的案件吗
The one that Katherine keeps throwing you off of?
我第一次也不是一蹴而就获得了她的青睐
I didn't win her love overnight the first time.
我有所进展  是吧
I'm making progress, huh?
彼得那个教职员女友查到哪了
Where are we on Peter's faculty girlfriend?
芭芭拉·利斯特罗姆博士
Dr. Barbara Lillstrom,
哈德逊大学心理学系主任
Head of the psych department at Hudson U.
上哈佛医学院时是尖子生
Top of her class at Harvard med school.
她指导彼得的毕业论文
She was advising Peter's senior thesis.
而且他们有不正当的师生恋关系
And they had an illicit student-faculty relationship,
当他拒绝她后  这关系以悲剧收场
one that ended ugly once he rejected her.
我打赌彼得已经对低分有心理准备
Yeah, I'm betting Peter was expecting
却没想到会被刺穿
a bad grade, not impalement.
我联系过心理学系
I contacted the psych department.
利斯特罗姆一整周都在外出
Lillstrom's been out all week.
她可能畏罪潜逃了
She could be on the run.
如果是的话  她没跑多远
If she is, she didn't run far.
或者至少她的手机没有
Or at least her phone didn't.
她的手机昨天失去了信号
Her cell signal went dead yesterday,
不过最后接收到信号的
but it last pinged off a tower
是一个无人居住的建筑外的信号塔
outside of a tenantless building here.
这里离彼得被杀的地方只有四个街区
That's four blocks away from where Peter was killed.
要知道  如果你想在昨晚
You know, if you want to curry favor with Katherine
那个小状况之后讨好凯瑟琳
after last night's little debacle,
你也许应该告诉她这件事
you might tell her about this.
不  首先  我们要确定利斯特罗姆在那里
No, first, we'll confirm Lillstrom is there.
然后我们再呼叫主力
Then we'll call in the cavalry.
这种时候  我希望你能随身持枪
Times like this, I wish you were more comfortable
而不是只放在你的桌子里
carrying a gun on your person, not just in your desk.
一名优秀的私家侦探靠的首先是他的聪明才智
A good P.I. relies on his wits first,
其次才是子弹
bullets second.
聪明才智先请
After your wits.
什么声音
What was that?
这解释了彼得为什么穿狱服
This explains Peter's prison jumpsuit.
-别动  -放轻松  伙计
- Don't move. - Easy there, fella.
除非你是纽约扬基棒球队
Unless you're a New York Yankee,
放弃试图盗上二垒吧
quit trying to steal second base.
说话小心点
Watch your mouth.
我只是说  先请我喝一杯
I'm just saying, buy me a drink first.
拿着这个
Take this.
来  打开四号
Here, open 4.
不  什么
No. What?
你确定要这么做
Are you sure about this?
我得去通知典狱长
I have to warn the Warden.
这是什么监狱
What kind of prison is this?
看看周围
Take a look around.
你注意到什么狱警和囚犯
You notice any similarities...
之间的共同点了吗
...between the guards and the inmates?
-等等  他们和我差不多大  -没错
- Wait -- they're all my age. - Exactly.
而且我打赌他们都是哈德逊大学的学生
And I'm betting they're all Hudson University students.
他们在重现斯坦福监狱实验
They're doing a re-enactment of the stanford prison experiment.
就是70年代
That thing from the '70s
通过让学生扮演囚犯和狱警
where they studied the psychological effects
来研究心理效应的那件事
of making students pretend to be prisoners and guards?
非常合理
Makes sense.
利斯特罗姆博士是心理学系的系主任
Dr. Lillstrom is head of the psych department.
除了她还有谁能有这样的权力
Who else is gonna have the kind of pull
来组织这样的事情
to put something like this together?
也许彼得像肖申克电影里那样越狱了
Maybe Peter shawshanked his way out of here.
彼得  他真的逃走了
Peter? He actually escaped?
你认识彼得
You know Peter?
他以前就被关在你这个牢房
He was in your cell,
但是有一天我们醒来发现他不见了
but one day we woke up and he was just gone.
-狱警怎么说  -他们很震惊
- What did the guards say? - They freaked.
他是怎么从牢房里逃出去的
How'd he get out of his cell?
但是我们  我们不知道
But we -- we didn't know
他们是不是只是在扰乱我们的思维
if they were just messing with our heads,
因为这是他们的惯用手法
'cause that's what they do here.
这是你自愿参加的吗
Did you volunteer for this?
我需要钱  但是现在我只想回家
I needed the money, but now I just want to go home.
等一下  你是说这里没有紧急呼救按钮
Wait a minute. Y-you mean, there's no panic button?
没有以防你想退出的安全措施
There's no safety mechanism if you want to quit?
以前有一面白旗
There was a white flag,
但彼得被降级之后他们就把它撤掉了
but they removed it when Peter was demoted.
彼得在当囚犯之前曾经是狱警
Peter was a guard before he was an inmate?
警卫长  典狱长利斯特罗姆任命的
Head guard, recruited by Warden Lillstrom.
但是他对我们很好
But he was nice to us.
我觉得这是利斯特罗姆放弃他的原因
I think that's why Lillstrom turned on him.
她把彼得变成囚犯  强迫他坐上那把椅子
She made Peter an inmate, forced him to sit in the chair.
什么样的椅子
What chair are we talking about?
我们的日常审问
Our daily interrogations.
我们被绑在椅子上
We're strapped to a chair.
利斯特罗姆在我们眼前反复播放影像
Lillstrom flashes images in our eyes over and over.
那些奇奇怪怪的光
All these strange lights.
利斯特罗姆想知道什么
What does Lillstrom want to know?
我们的秘密  越见不得人越好
Our secrets. The darker, the better.
那种感觉就像是她围着你的脑子打转
It's like she's sliding around your brain,
窥视你的灵魂
peeking into your soul.
打开牢房
Come open this cell.
这里我说了算  犯人
I give the orders here, inmate.
成绩我说了算
And I give the grades.
你看到我的教职身份证明了
You saw my faculty ID.
所以这是随堂测试
So, here's the pop quiz.
不开牢门将会导致
Failure to open this cell will cause
你的学术生涯彻底断送
an oh-so-disastrous end to your academic career --
对还是错
True or false?
她的也打开
Hey. Hers too.
立刻带我们去见利斯特罗姆博士
Take us to Dr. Lillstrom right now.
典狱长  我们有麻烦了
Warden. We, um, have a problem.
是有麻烦了  几年的计划和研究  全毁了
Damn right we do -- years of planning, of research, ruined!
你知不知道你给我造成了多大损失
Do you have any idea of the damage you've caused?
我才不管
Ask me if I care.
我们是来调查彼得被杀一案
We're here investigating Peter's murder.
彼得死了
Peter's dead?
他逃走了  这不关我的事
Look, he broke out. That's not my responsibility.
纽约是个危险之地
New York's a dangerous town.
你和彼得的关系我们都知道了
We know all about your relationship with Peter.
我是他论文的指导老师
I'm the adviser on his thesis.
你对他的指导可不只是论文
You advised him on a lot more than that.
你们俩有一腿
You were having an affair.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我们发现了你的性爱小囚室
We found your little sex dungeon
还有你留在镜子上的信息
and the message you wrote on the mirror.
彼得是不是和你提出分手
Peter broke up with you, didn't he?
所以你让他成为你的囚犯
So you punished him the only way you knew how --
以此来惩罚他
by making him your prisoner.
后来他逃跑了
Then he escaped.
那时你才决定杀他灭口吧  博士
Is that when you decided he had to die, doctor?
你杀了彼得
You killed Peter?
没有  我什么都没做过
I-it's not true. Any of it.
-跟我走一趟   -什么
- You're coming with me. - Wha--
把这些牢房打开
You open those cells,
但在我和警方来之前任何人不准离开这
but no one leaves here until I've returned with the police.
别听他的
Do not listen to him.
你在室内这里又一片漆黑
Oh, and, uh, you're indoors and it's dark,
把眼镜摘了  看起来像个傻缺
so take off the sunglasses. You look stupid.
又搞定一个案子
Yet another case closed
理查德·卡塞尔事务所为您效劳
courtesy of Richard Castle Investigations.
这个女人是谁
Um, who is this woman?
你的手被铐了
And are you in handcuffs?
这个人绑架了我
This man abducted me.
不是绑架  我这是公民逮捕
It's not an abduction. It's a citizen's arrest.
请你搞清楚
Please get it straight.
贝克特  这位是利斯特罗姆博士
Beckett, please meet Dr. Lillstrom.
她是彼得的老师  俩人有私情
She was Peter's teacher -- with benefits.
十分重口味的那种
The real kinky kind, too.
但当彼得要结束这种关系时
But when Peter ended their trysts,
她把他秘密囚禁在了地下监狱实验里
she locked him up in a secret, underground prison experiment,
我就是在那抓了她
which is where I caught her.
不用谢  亲
You're welcome, honey.
你去了地下囚室
You went to an underground prison?
一个人
Alone?
不是一个人  阿莱克西斯和我一起
No, not alone. I had Alexis with me.
你有支援就好
Oh, well, since you had backup.
你逗我吗卡塞尔  你女儿
Are you kidding, Castle? Your daughter?
听你这说话的语气  我像个坏家长
When you say it in that tone, I sound like a bad parent.
总之  利斯特罗姆博士是疑犯
Regardless, Dr. Lillstrom is a suspect.
-相信我  -好吧
- Trust me. - Fine.
谢谢
Thanks.
警察局有警察局的规矩  你知道的
There's protocol. You know that.
如果你有线索  应该通知我们
If you had a lead, you should have called us.
我是想这么做  但他们把我们囚禁了
Oh, believe me, I wanted to, but they locked us up in a cell.
不  我是说  你应该先通知我们
No, I mean, you should have called us be--
什么  把你俩关了
Wait, they locked you up?
好吧  算了  我不想知道
You know what? Never mind. I don't want to know.
去找莱恩和埃斯波带他们去监狱
Just go find Ryan and Espo and take them to the prison.
这个人疯了
That man is insane.
我是清白的
I'm innocent.
如果他说你有嫌疑
If he says you're a suspect,
相信我  你和清白就说再见吧
then trust me -- you are far from innocent.
走吧
Let's go.
这里  伙计们
This way, guys.
不
Oh, no.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no!
我叫他们待在这的
I told them to stay.
他们又不是狗  他们是大学生
They're not dogs, Castle. They're college kids.
还指望他们听话啊
What did you expect?
这里已经完全被清空了
This place has been completely cleared out.
利斯特罗姆博士肯定有应急计划
Dr. Lillstrom must have had a contingency plan.
他们把证据都清理干净了
They took all the evidence.
我却没能阻止他们
And I let it happen.
只因我想在贝克特面前表现
All because I wanted to impress Beckett.
对不起  贝克特  是我搞砸了
Sorry, Beckett, I screwed up.
没错  是搞砸了
Yeah, you did.
我破坏了整个案子的调查
And I jeopardized the entire case.
是的  就是你
Again, yes.
但是要你知道
But you know what?
如果不是你  我们还一直以为
If it wasn't for you, then we'd still be thinking
彼得身上的囚衣是万圣节服装
that Peter's prison uniform was a halloween costume.
我查过利斯特罗姆博士的资料
So, I've been digging into Dr. Lillstrom.
你们知道在过去十年里
Did you know that for the past decade,
她一直和军方有合约  进行心理实验
she's been contracting with the army, working psy ops?
等等
Wait a minute.
监狱实验是海军首创
The Navy funded the first,
最早的斯坦福监狱实验
The original Stanford prison experiment.
也许在利斯特罗姆博士背后
Maybe the army is behind
有军方在支持她重现实验
Dr. Lillstrom's modern-day incarnation.
这就解释了为何证据清理如此之快
That would explain how the place was scrubbed so quickly.
为什么军方会对
Now, why would the military be interested
大学生囚室扮演这么有兴趣
in a bunch of college students playing prison?
政府需要
Well, the government's in need of
针对千禧世代年轻人的
new counterterrorism techniques
新的反恐技术
aimed at the millennial generation --
如何进入年轻恐怖分子的思想和击溃他们
How to get into the minds of young terrorists and break them.
还有什么比就地取材
And what better source of lab rats
更方便的呢
than the millennials here at home?
但我们永远拿不到监控录影带
But we'll never get those surveillance tapes back.
我们怎么证明彼得逃跑之后
So how do we prove that Lillstrom left the prison
利斯特罗姆离开囚室杀了他
to kill Peter after he escaped?
我们要她自己招供
We need a confession.
博士喜欢玩心理战是吧
Well, the doc likes mind games, right?
要么起诉我要么放了我
Charge me or let me go.
你觉得哪个比较好
Which sounds better --
是过失刑罚导致他人精神痛苦
Negligent infliction of emotional distress,
还是毛骨悚然的心理虐待
or gross psychological abuse?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在写电邮给哈德逊大学全体教员
I'm writing an e-mail to the entire Hud U. Faculty.
我想让大家都知道
Figured I'd let everyone know
你在用在校学生的身体
that you were conducting an unauthorized experiment
实施一项非法的实验
with members of the student body,
且是由美国军方秘密资助的
secretly funded by the U.S. Military.
我倒想看看你有什么证据
I'd love to see you prove it,
尤其是因为所有参与的学生
especially because every participating student
都签了保密协定
signs a nondisclosure agreement.
好吧  那我想你不介意我发出去吧
Oh. Well, then, I suppose you won't mind if I send this.
等等
Wait! Wait.
你要我怎么做
What will it take for you
才不把这件事告诉哈德逊大学的任何人
not to tell anyone at Hudson about this?
说出真相
The truth.
你能说到做到么  警监
Do I have your word, Captain?
我不会向哈德逊大学告密的
Hud U. will never hear from me.
好吧
Okay.
我没有杀彼得  也没和他发生过关系
I didn't kill Peter, and I wasn't sleeping with him.
你就这些料么
That's all you got?
那我可发送了
Well, then I'm sending it.
我说的是事实
Look, it's the truth!
彼得逃跑那晚  我并不在囚室
The night Peter escaped, I wasn't even at the prison.
那你在哪
Then where were you?
我公寓的管子爆了  搞了一整晚
A pipe burst in my apartment. I was dealing with it all night.
你去找门卫确认
Check with my doorman.
但如果你在怀疑是
But if you're thinking
和彼得有私情的人杀了他
whoever was having an affair with Peter killed him...
我想我能提供帮助
I might be able to help.
这才像话
Now we're talking.
我的研究是对实验对象强行获取秘密
My study deals with extracting secrets from unwilling subjects.
彼得透露了他有私情了吗
And Peter revealed that he was having an affair?
他和谁发生过关系
So, who was he sleeping with?
你群邮名单里的某个人
Someone on that list.
费勒主任  我想你知道此行的原因
Dean Feller, I'm sure you know why you're here.
事实上  我不知道
Actually, I don't.
我们找到了那间公寓
Well, we found the studio apartment.
我不  不知道这是什么
I don't -- I don't know w-what that is.
真的么
Really?
我们把你的照片给隔壁住户看
Because we showed your photo to the neighbors.
-他们都说这是  -好吧
- They were able to tell us that  - Okay.
彼得连续好几个晚上都放了我鸽子
Look. Peter stood me up a couple of nights in a row.
我很受伤  所以就写下留言
And I was hurt, so I wrote him a message.
彼得放你鸽子是因为
Peter stood you up because he was trapped
他被关在利斯特罗姆博士的监狱实验里
inside of Dr. Lillstrom's prison experiment.
什么监狱实验
What prison experiment?
彼得跟你说过他陷入了怎样的境地
Peter told you about the hell that he was stuck in.
你的电话记录表明你接到过一个
Phone records show that you received a collect call
来自犯罪现场附近的公用电话打来的收方付费电话
from a payphone near the crime scene.
是的  彼得打过电话给我  他吓坏了
Yes, Peter called me. He was panicked.
他让我去公园接他
He told me to pick him up at the park
然后他会向我解释一切
and he would explain everything,
但他从没提到过任何关于监狱的事
but he never said anything about a prison.
他根本就没出现
He never showed.
彼得有没有告诉你
Did Peter tell you
利斯特罗姆博士从他那里得知了你们偷情的事
that Dr. Lillstrom extracted the secret of your affair?
你就是因此才杀害他的吗
Is that why you killed him?
因为他是唯一一个可以证明真相的人
Because he was the only one who could verify the truth?
什么
What?
我没杀彼得
I didn't kill Peter.
我要律师  现在就要
I want a lawyer right now.
你不信  对吧
You're not buying this, are you?
没有认罪  也没有确凿证据
No confession. No smoking gun.
简直太不干净利索了
It's just...not clean.
有时候凶杀案就这样
Well, that's how homicides are sometimes.
你知道的
You know that.
是的  但是我还是觉得有些困扰
Yeah, but something's still bothering me.
还有一部分谜底没有被揭开
There's a part of the mystery that hasn't been solved yet.
我们漏了故事中的一部分
We're missing part of the story.
你认为我们要怎么找回它呢
And how do you suggest we find it?
用我们一直以来的老办法
The same way we always do.
从头开始  回到那个监狱去
We start at the beginning, back at the prison.
你只想找个借口跟我独处
You just want an excuse to get me alone.
不  贝克特  我想得到真相
No, Beckett, I just want the truth.
那天晚上彼得到底经历了什么
What really happened to Peter that night.
彼得被关在这间牢房里
Peter was placed in this cell.
接着他越狱了
And then he escaped.
是的  但他怎么做到的
Yeah, but how?
他们说有天早上醒来他突然就不见了
They said one morning he was just gone.
你在想什么
So, what are you thinking?
你认为彼得越狱的方式跟他被害有关吗
How Peter escaped had something to do with who killed him?
只有一个办法能验证了
Only one way to figure it out.
你猜怎么着
And guess what.
咱俩要一起来验证
We're gonna figure it out together.
不会有信号的
You are not gonna get a signal.
你是故意把我困在这的
You trapped me in here on purpose.
不  我没有
No, I didn't.
不过既然你提到这个  告诉我
But since you brought it up, tell me --
你为什么会觉得自己被困在我们的婚姻中了
why do you feel trapped in our marriage?
我没有
I don't.
那你为什么要离开
Then why did you leave?
原因很复杂
It's complicated.
越狱也很复杂
So is breaking out of a prison,
所以我们现在有时间好好谈谈
so we've got some time.
我不要跟你聊这个
You know what? We're not having this conversation.
我让你给我空间
I asked you for space,
而你却把我关在一个监狱牢房里
and you literally locked me up in a jail cell.
好吧  好吧  好吧
Okay. Whoa, whoa, whoa -- okay. Okay.
你  我给你空间就是了  我给你空间
You -- I'll give you space. I'll give you space.
你知道吗
You know what?
我运气一向不好
You know, it would be just my luck
子弹一定会弹回来打到你
it would ricochet and hit you
这样我一下子救要应付两起谋杀案了
and then I'd have two murders to contend with.
听我说  放轻松
Look, relax.
彼得既然都逃出去了  我们也可以
Peter broke out of here, so...so can we.
也许吧
Probably.
你说的没错
You're right.
咱们一起被困在过更糟糕的地方
I mean, we've been stuck in worse places together before.
我喜欢那个词  一起
I like that word -- together.
到底怎么回事  凯特  我做错什么了
So what happened, Kate? What did I do wrong?
卡塞尔  这件事与你无关
Castle, this one's not about you.
是我的问题
It's on me.
我爱你
I love you.
我会永远爱你
I always will.
那就想想办法  去做心理咨询  婚姻辅导
Then let's work it out -- therapy, counseling.
只要能挽救婚姻就行
Whatever it takes.
我  我不能
I -- I just can't.
为什么
Why?
你哼什么
"Huh," what?
这个地方被改成监狱之前
Before this place was a prison cell,
是个办公楼对吧
it was an office building, right?
抬头看看
Take a look up.
我敢打赌彼得就是这么逃出去的
I bet you that's how Peter got out.
来吧  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
你该把我托上去了
Uh, this is when you boost me up.
没错  上去
Uh, right. Up.
准备好了  上去
Ready. There we go.
好的
Uh, okay.
我上来了
Oh, got it.
你干得不错亲爱的  我不是催你  可是
You're doing great, honey. N-not to rush you, but...
等一下  哪里不对劲
Wait a minute. Something's not right here.
彼得在牢房里怎么够到通风孔的
How did Peter reach the vent from inside the cell?
这得两个人合作才行
It was a two-man job.
两个犯人逃了
Two prisoners escaped,
但是却只少了一个人  也就是说
but only one was missing, which means...
凶手又回来了
The killer came back!
我给你开门
I'll open the door.
谢谢你能来警局配合调查  艾米莉
Thanks for coming down to the station, Emily.
我们想问你几个问题  是关于监狱实验的
We just have a few questions about the prison experiment...
以及你是怎么帮助彼得逃出去的
and how you helped Peter escape from it.
你们说什么
What are you talking about?
彼得把手伸过铁栏  把你托上去
Well, Peter reached through the bars, and he hoisted you up,
然后你们俩一块逃出去了  不是吗
and you both escaped, didn't you?
然后你在公园里杀了彼得
And then you killed Peter in the park
又回到了监狱  回到了你的牢房里
and returned to the prison, to your cell --
完美的不在场证明
the perfect alibi.
这太荒唐了  我为什么要杀他
That's ridiculous. Why would I kill him?
艾米莉  我们知道奖学金的事
Emily, we know about the scholarship.
你需要奖学金才能继续学业
You needed it to stay in school.
但他胜的光明正大
Yeah, but he won fair and square.
我们知道这不是真的
We know that's not true.
彼得之所以能获得奖学金
Peter won that scholarship
是因为他跟院长有私情
because he was having an affair with the dean.
当你在监狱里得知这件事后
And then when you found out about it in the prison,
你便报复了他
you took your revenge.
不是我
It wasn't me.
-别撒谎了  艾米莉  -那不是我
- Stop lying, Emily! - It wasn't!
那是另一个不同的我
It was a different me!
那个实验把我逼疯了
That experiment messed with my head!
我们逃走之后  我就  我就崩溃了
After we escaped, I just...snapped.
太不公平了
It was so unfair.
我那么努力  事事都做到最好
I had worked so hard, did everything right.
当彼得跑进公园后
When Peter ran into the park,
我在后面跟着他
I-I went after him.
然后我就看到了那根树枝
Then I saw that tree branch.
我为什么要那么做
Why did I do that?
谢谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting me.
我整理了一下资料  方便我们继续调查
I finished piecing this together for our investigation.
你开始犹豫了
You're having second thoughts.
对吧
Aren't you?
是的  我知道这件事会很难
Yeah. I just knew that this was gonna be tough.
但没想到这么难
I didn't think it was gonna be like this.
我明白  真的
I get it. I do.
也许在我们开始前要先停一停
Look, maybe we need to stop before we start.
贝克特  我听你的
Beckett, I'll follow your lead.
我们该怎么办
What should we do?
开始工作吧
Let's get to work.
那是
That is...
50年陈酿的威士忌
50-year-old scotch.
没错  我买了一整箱
Yeah. I bought a case of it.
阿丽克西斯  那很贵的
Alexis, that's expensive.
别担心  爸  是公司付的钱
Relax, dad. The company paid for it.
好吧
Oh, okay.
等一下  那也就是我给的钱
W-wait. That means I paid for it.
敬案子告破
To closing the case.
敬大手大脚的公款消费
To generous expense accounts.
你跟贝克特之间有进展吗
So, any progress with Beckett?
在监狱的时候  我们
You know, at the prison, we,
有那么一会深情交流
um, sort of had a moment.
真的吗
Really?
我想我的计划起效了
I think my plan is working.
肯定会起效的  对吧
I mean, it has to, right?
这样吧
Um, you know what?
咱们来立个传统
We're gonna start a tradition.
以后我们每破一个案子都要一起做
For when we solve a case together.
我不抽烟  你也不抽
I don't smoke, and neither do you.
谁说要抽烟了
Who said anything about smoking?